♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSICAL STING) ♪
RECRUITER: (ECHOING) Jump.
(ECHOING WHOOSH)
♪ (EERIE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
- (GRUNTS)
- (PIGEONS COOING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪ (EERIE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Hmm.
(SIGHS)
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(DOOR HINGES CREAKING)
♪ (MUSIC SWELLS) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
Hello.
I'm here for the interview.
- Please have a seat inside.
- Yeah
I'll be back
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING)
(TRAFFIC RUMBLING)
- (DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
- (PIGEON COOING)
(TRAFFIC RUMBLING)
(TRAFFIC RUMBLING, HONKING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(TRAFFIC RUMBLING)
You haven't moved.
I was told to wait.
Did you stay here all night?
You said, "Have a seat."
Do you know who I am?
I have a pretty good idea.
You're a Guardian.
And what have you been
told about us?
You are the ruling body
of the cosmos,
founder of the Lanterns.
There were 12 of you.
One of you recently died.
My condolences.
Thank you.
Also, you're all blue.
We believe this interview
will be more pleasurable...
if I am in human form.
- May I ask you a question?
- Please.
Green Lanterns
are chosen by rings.
So why, suddenly, are you
interviewing people for the job?
Because of your condolences.
♪ (BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Am I supposed to say something?
This is when most candidates
ask, "Why me?"
Oh.
No. I know exactly why me.
(JOHN STEWART JUNIOR
COOS, WHIMPERS)
MARCUS STEWART:
(DISTANTLY) Mama!
Mama!
BERNADETTE STEWART:
I'm coming, Marcus.
♪ (INTRIGUING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(RING WARBLING)
- (CONSTRUCT PULSING)
- (JOHN STEWART SENIOR GASPS)
- ♪ (ENIGMATIC MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- DISEMBODIED VOICE:
Are you afraid?
JOHN SENIOR: (GRUNTS) Yes!
Yes!
(CONSTRUCT WHOOSHING)
(JOHN SENIOR GASPING)
- (CRIES)
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- What happened?
- (GRUNTS)
- (PANTING)
- (JOHN CRYING)
Oh my God.
(GASPS)
(CRIES)
♪ (DRAMATIC
SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
The mysterious hero
known only as Green Lantern
has again saved a major city
from near catastrophe.
Still no information exists
about his identity,
but today, he has offered
this statement.
Quoting now,
"Though you can't see my face,
know that my commitment
to fighting evil
will never waver.
The night I received this ring,
I was asked only one question,
if I was afraid.
I remain as steadfast now
as I was then.
I am fearless."
(GUNSHOT)
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- (JOHN CRYING)
- Are you out of your mind?
- (JOHN WAILING)
How the fuck was I not supposed
to be scared?
Got lifted out of my bed.
- I was in a... a bubble.
- Give me the gun, Johnny.
JOHN SENIOR:
The light was green.
It was a test
to be this Lantern thing,
and they wanted me.
We have been through this.
It was a nightmare.
- There was no bubble!
- There was. He just said it.
Give me the pistol, Johnny.
They asked him the same thing
they asked me.
Oh, you think
that's a coincidence?
- (SOFTLY) You're scaring me.
- "Are you afraid?"
(JOHN CRYING)
Why you don't believe me?
Because it's unbelievable!
But you better believe
if you don't hand me that gun,
I will send you to your maker!
(JOHN WHIMPERS, COOS)
(SOFTLY) I... I wasn't
gonna hurt nobody, Bernie.
- (CHAMBER CLICKS)
- (BULLET CLATTERING)
This thing
has got your mind gone,
and we can't do this anymore.
And when we come home
from school,
you better be gone!
♪ (BROODING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (CLOCK TICKING)
- (DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(DOG BARKING IN DISTANCE)
LIANNA:
Is Sergeant Stewart available?
He's not.
Can I help you?
- At what hour do you expect him?
- I'm not sure.
Who are you?
Are you Sergeant Stewart's wife?
- Bernadette.
- Please tell your husband
the Guardians
send their deepest regrets
for any lingering trauma
caused by
our latest communication.
We would like
to make compensation
for any continued distress
that may have resulted.
I don't understand,
I... (SIGHS)
We have reports
that many of the candidates
considered for the role
of Green Lantern
have been experiencing...
emotional turmoil.
Are you telling me
you're an alien?
I am an intergalactic species
non-native to your Earth, yes.
Prove it.
Excuse me? (CHUCKLES)
You just look like some
unfortunate White lady to me.
Prove it.
I've found my natural form
to be upsetting to humans.
I don't get upset.
Show me.
♪ (TENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (LOW RUMBLING)
- (FABRIC CREAKING, RIPPING)
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
You drink coffee?
Sorry for the mess.
My kids just had a test.
You have more children
than this?
I do. I meant my students.
I'm a teacher.
So, you floated my husband
out of our bed?
We have never had
a Green Lantern from Earth.
We realize now that
the ring's selection process
is unusual
for your species.
Do you all intend
on fixing this?
Everyone he talks to thinks
Johnny's lost his mind.
He's nearly drinking himself
to death every night.
My family is falling apart.
The system is imperfect.
This is the best I can do.
Do you know the differences
in race on Earth?
Do you understand
how unfair it is
to ask a Black man in America
if he's afraid?
By "Black," you mean...
brown skin?
We are terrified daily
of persecution
and still show up,
sometimes better,
than everyone around us.
Did you know that?
- I did not.
- (BERNADETTE SCOFFS)
Even in space,
y'all don't consider us.
- ♪ (PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (JOHN COOING)
Humans have
relatively short lifespans.
Perhaps this could
present opportunities.
Whatever the ring saw
in your husband
is in his genetic makeup.
You are a very formidable woman.
Your offspring could one day...
be an excellent candidate.
That's a long time from now.
What... what if he's scared too?
LIANNA: Then he'd fail.
And if I raise him
to be fearless?
That would certainly warrant
our attention...
when the time came.
And when the time comes,
how do I know
he'll get a fair shot?
You have my word.
(JOHN COOING)
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
Were you the one
that came to visit my mom?
Yes.
JOHN: You know,
the police came to visit her
when she tried
to cash that diamond.
They didn't believe it was hers.
I am sorry
she had to go through that.
Yeah, I'll pass that along.
Your father was a Marine.
Is that why you became one too?
Yes, ma'am.
And it's, uh, part of the path.
The path?
I became a Marine
so I could get here,
across the table from you.
Well, let's start there,
John Stewart.
Or, Sergeant Major John Stewart.
- Is that right?
- Formerly Sergeant Major.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(JOHN EXHALES)
You don't have other clothes
in your car, uh...?
- Gym bag?
- No, sir.
Well, I ordered.
I got you a steak and a beer.
- Thank you.
- Weren't supposed to be dressed.
I was told this was about
an issue of national security.
The whole point of meeting
at an Outback is to be discreet.
Not a lot of snipers
like you left.
Your kill record's impeccable.
- You're patient.
- Is this my target?
CHAVEZ: Code name is Gray Wolf.
- He launders money.
- I don't care about the man.
- Tell me about the mission.
- He's impossible to track.
There's only one place
we've ever known him to return.
A retreat we believe he owns
in the Kamchatka Peninsula.
We have no idea how often
he goes, how long he stays.
You want me to wait on him,
stay there until he shows up.
It could take weeks,
maybe a couple months.
And how many have been
before me?
What makes you think
you're not the first?
Well, there's intel
on an otherwise remote
mountain range,
a rudimentary map
of the retreat,
so someone's been there.
Three.
We lost contact
with the last team months ago.
But if you agree to the mission,
we'll do things differently.
You'll have a panic button
if you need extraction.
I don't want that.
I don't do panic, sir.
Best to get your affairs
in order before you leave.
- Yeah.
- CHAVEZ: How's your dad?
Sir?
We were stationed together
after... after basic, uh...
I heard he had some struggles.
Much better, sir. Thank you.
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
I didn't hear you come in.
Couch getting too comfortable?
JOHN SENIOR:
It's better than a motel.
We need to fix this, Johnny.
I know.
BERNADETTE: You were never
gonna wear that ring.
- I know you don't believe me.
- BERNADETTE: I do now.
And I'm sorry that
everybody's been treating you
like you're crazy.
- I'm sorry I have.
- Why now? What changed?
(DIAMOND THUDS)
One of the Green Lantern's
bosses came by the other day.
They apologized
for not picking you.
- What did they say?
- (SCOFFS)
Some bullshit about
the imperfection of the system.
But it could be John.
JOHN SENIOR: Our baby?
- That's right.
- Huh.
- I don't understand.
- Why did you become a Marine?
Why do I get up and teach?
To be better
than where we came from,
to prove to God-knows-who
that we are worth a damn.
And we didn't break
every stereotype
and face down every fear
for you to be penalized
because you're scared to leave
the people that you love.
They don't see us, Bernie,
and you know that.
Down here or up there.
BERNADETTE:
I said the same thing,
but we can't accept that.
We can't raise three boys
and believe that no matter
how good they are,
- they get looked over.
- Why not Aaron or Marcus?
No, they're too old. Um...
They already know fear.
Plus, I think
the Guardian liked John.
- I could tell.
- (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
♪ (SOFT PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
How do you make a Green Lantern?
I've been reading.
We condition him
so he's used to fear.
Train him to be everything
they saw in you
and everything
the Lantern they picked isn't.
I don't know.
The night that they rejected you
was the beginning
of everything falling apart.
This is a chance for us
to put it back together.
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
He's gonna hate us.
So be it.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
- (PLANE ENGINE ROARING)
- ♪ (DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
It's not ideal jumping weather,
but it's the only way
they don't see us.
Then it's ideal.
MARINE:
When the mission is complete,
hit this button.
If anything goes wrong
and you need extraction...
You'll hear from me
when the mission's complete.
Good luck. Jump.
- (HATCH WHIRRING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
♪ (INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (PARACHUTE WHOOSHING)
- (WIND ROARING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(BRANCHES SNAPPING)
(JOHN GROANS)
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (GASPS)
- ♪ (MUSIC FALLS) ♪
- (THUNDER RUMBLING)
- (PANTS, COUGHS)
- (PANTING)
- ♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
I was dishonorably discharged.
- Elaborate.
- Which part?
The dishonorable
or the discharge?
I am more concerned
with disobedience.
JOHN: No disobedience.
I had a mission to complete
and I failed.
You don't present as someone
who relents without cause.
Well, if there was a reason
or a cause,
that would be classified.
Much of what I will discuss
will also be classified.
You have my word
nothing leaves this room.
- What do you know
about Sinestro?
- ♪ (OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Only what I saw on the news.
He went rogue.
He killed
one of your fellow Guardians.
Hal Jordan beat his ass
and locked him up.
And what do you think
of Hal Jordan?
- I don't.
- LIANNA: You don't what?
- I don't think about him.
- You must think something.
He was chosen
instead of your father.
My dad served
this country honorably.
He respects anyone
whose job it is
to protect people.
He taught me to do the same.
- Sinestro was Jordan's teacher.
- ♪ (BROODING SYNTH
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
A father figure.
He still harbors deep affection
for his mentor.
It's quite...
troubling.
JOHN: It's human.
We love the people
that raise us.
Even if they're crazy.
- (PIGEON WINGS FLAPPING)
- GROUP: (ECHOING)
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear John ♪
(BOTH CHEERING)
Make a wish, my boy.
- (BLOWS)
- (JOHN SENIOR CHUCKLES)
We got something for you, baby.
(WHISPERS) Close your eyes.
Why are you closing
your eyes, Marcus?
I want it be a baseball jersey.
You can't fit your gut
in John's shirts.
- Hey.
- (JOHN CHUCKLING)
- Open it.
- Whoa!
(BERNADETTE SIGHS)
Wait, I asked for crayons.
Your father and I think
five is old enough
to know about your destiny.
♪ (SOFT PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
♪ (RIVETING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC OVERLAPPING) ♪
You're gonna be
the Green Lantern
when you grow up, son.
You probably wondered
why we treat you so different.
Sleep in a different room
than your brothers,
don't go to school with them.
I thought
you just liked him better.
Hey!
BERNADETTE:
Boys, this is serious.
When you were a baby,
the Guardians,
the people
that run the whole universe,
came to tell us
that they want you
to be the next Green Lantern.
They said that
we had to train you
and they would send birds
to watch over us.
They report back
to the Guardians.
That's why
you like birds so much, son.
Now, I know you like drawing,
and you wanted those crayons,
and you can still do that
a little.
But this year,
your real training starts.
What do I have to do?
They want us to make sure
that you're fearless.
- (SIGHS) You always choose him.
- Hey, Aaron.
Hey.
You can't worry about him.
You can't worry about anybody
but yourself.
You don't want
the Guardians to think
- you don't wanna do it, right?
- No, ma'am.
(PAPER RUSTLING)
MARCUS: What's this?
Careful, Marcus.
Hand it to John.
We've given you
your target, son.
Now you gotta learn to shoot.
You ready?
LIANNA: Is that why you chose
to be a sniper?
- Uh, I'm a good shot.
- That is not what I'm asking.
I can hit a target
from over a mile away.
- ♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (JOHN GRUNTS)
LIANNA:
So, you like the distance?
JOHN: Is that a metaphor?
You asking me
if I'm close to anyone,
or if I'll be distracted
on the job?
- (YELPS)
- LIANNA: Yes.
That is what I'm asking.
JOHN: I like being alone,
and I don't get distracted.
♪ (MUSIC RISES) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FALLS) ♪
LIANNA: And your parents?
Do you resent them
for the rigors of your training?
Do you have a family?
We come into existence alone,
and we die the same.
That's sad.
Is it?
I can't really explain family
to someone who doesn't have one,
but rigorous kind of comes
with the territory.
(GUNSHOT)
Hey, that was good, boy.
That was real good.
Go on over there
and set up another apple.
Aren't you supposed
to be out here
finishing this dish?
I thought
it made more sense to train.
You thought?
There's nothing to think about.
We have to finish the dish.
Diamond money's gone, Bernie.
We still need more parts.
And I need to call 'em
and tell 'em
how good he's doing.
We don't even know who to call,
and they said
they'll be watching.
I'm not leaving this up to them.
JOHN:
Look, Daddy. Like William Tell.
Shoot one off me.
♪ (UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Do it.
- What?
- See if he's afraid. Do it.
(SIGHS)
Fear is contagious.
Ask him what they asked you.
Are you afraid?
No, sir.
This is what it takes.
For the both of you.
♪ (MUSIC SWELLS) ♪
- ♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
- (BULLET CLINKING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
It's applesauce. Can I eat some?
♪ (SOFT PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
I think your father
can do better than that.
You deserve
a cheeseburger, boy.
(CHUCKLING) My boy. Come on.
LIANNA: And your parents,
do you love them?
Yes. Of course, I love them.
I owe them everything.
- You owe them?
- JOHN: Yes.
LIANNA: And how do you intend
to repay them?
- By getting this job.
- And what if you don't?
I will.
- How can you be so sure?
- I was trained to be sure.
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
- ♪ (THRILLING MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- ♪ ("ATLIENS" BY OUTKAST
PLAYING OVER RADIO) ♪
- AARON STEWART: You trippin'.
- MARCUS: No, I know I'm right.
- AARON: That's not what it says.
- MARCUS: Says.
- AARON: Yes, it is.
They just can't say the "S" word
on the radio.
Are the real words to this song,
"You like fish and grits
and all the pimp shit"?
And how would he know?
He ain't even Black.
That nigga listen
to piano music.
- You know
Mama makes him do that.
- AARON: (SHUSHES) Be quiet.
You know Mama makes him do that.
But he be listening
through the wall.
I hear him.
Yeah. That's the real words.
- I told you!
- You just saying that
so Aaron will like you.
(SCOFFS) Please.
You know all the words?
Do it.
You gonna be afraid of them
your whole life?
They tryna make you lame.
(RAPPING ALONG TO SONG)
♪ I said throw your hands
In the air ♪
♪ And wave 'em
Like you just don't care ♪
♪ And if you like fish and grits
And all that pimp shit ♪
♪ Everybody, let me
Hear you say ♪
- "Oh-yea-er"?
- (BOTH LAUGH)
- AARON: "Ay-er!"
- "Oh-yea-er."
(IN POSH VOICE) He talks like
a White boy named Henry.
(LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
- (TIRES SCREECHING)
- ♪ (SONG CUTS OFF) ♪
- BERNADETTE: John, get out.
- But, Mama, we asked him to rap.
This ain't about no song.
This is training.
He can't survive out there.
He's never in places like this--
If we wanted your input,
we'd have asked for it.
♪ (UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
Get out the car, son.
(WHISPERS) Sorry.
(HELICOPTER BLADES
WHIRRING OVERHEAD)
(ENGINE REVVING)
♪ (BROODING STRING
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (DISTANT SHOUTING)
- (GLASS BOTTLES CLINKING)
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- (METAL FENCE RATTLING)
(DISTANT DOG BARKING)
- All right there, son?
- What's up, little man?
LIANNA: I am curious
why you didn't hit
your panic button.
I had a mission to complete.
Perhaps you were stubborn.
LIANNA: Hmm.
Your training must have resulted
in great loneliness.
As humans require high levels
of social connection,
that isolation appears to be
in direct opposition
to your programming.
Humans aren't programmed,
we're raised.
I do not understand
the distinction.
Well, there is one.
♪ (BROODING STRING
MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
(AARON AND MARCUS CHATTERING,
CHUCKLING)
AARON:
Oh, where you going?
- I'm gonna... You can't do that.
- (MARCUS CHUCKLING)
- AARON: Wait! No. Go, go.
- MARCUS: No, no, no! (CHUCKLES)
- (GRUNTS)
- Oh! Yeah.
- (SOFT THUD)
- AARON: Ow! (LAUGHS)
BERNADETTE: John.
I saved you a pork chop.
Your plate's in the microwave.
♪ (SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(JOHN SOBBING)
LIANNA: Should you become
Green Lantern,
you'll become more isolated
from your family.
Not a problem.
They will not...
- miss you?
- JOHN: No.
LIANNA: You will not miss them?
We all lived in the same house
for 18 years.
I grew up missing them.
♪ (SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES) ♪
- Mama!
- (BERNADETTE
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Can I go outside
with Marcus and Aaron?
- I did my work.
- BERNADETTE: He can already
shoot over a quarter mile...
- Mama?
- ...at ten years old.
He demonstrates fearlessness
every day.
- He-- Are you there?
- (BUTTON CLICKING)
Just say something.
You gave your word!
- (STATIC OVER RADIO)
- JOHN: Who are you talking to?
(SIGHS)
Was that the Guardians?
Why weren't they talking back?
Maybe they're not talking
because they're not
seeing results.
- You're still scared.
- I'm not scared of nothing.
The birds should be
telling them that.
- BERNADETTE: Well, they're not.
- Then the birds are liars.
- Prove it.
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
(GUNSHOT)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
- (DOGS BARKING)
That's good, John.
That's real good.
Let's go get you a cheeseburger.
- He's not done.
- Say what?
Let John shoot.
Shoot what?
The apple off you.
He said he's not scared.
Let's see.
Can you do that, son?
♪ (UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(BIRDS CONTINUE CHIRPING)
Honey, shouldn't
we work up to this?
John could shoot a moth
out the sky.
Yeah.
(CLEARS THROAT)
♪ (BROODING STRING
MUSIC OVERLAPPING) ♪
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
♪ (MUSIC SWELLS) ♪
♪ (MUSIC FALLS) ♪
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(BIRD CAWING)
Guess the birds
aren't liars after all.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
- (DOOR OPENS)
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
BERNADETTE:
You don't have to do that.
Let me see.
You are gifted, son.
I know if it were up to you,
you'd do
a whole lot more drawing.
I gotta train.
There's no time for drawing.
Doesn't mean
you wanna do it any less.
Some things just come natural.
Like birds, drawing...
loving your dad.
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
You know how many little boys
don't even get a daddy to love?
I was scared.
♪ (TENDER MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
It's normal
to not wanna hurt
the people you love.
Love is the most important thing
we've got.
It's why we train you so hard.
We wanna see you succeed
because we love you.
The birds were right.
I'm not good enough.
I made the birds up.
We make this all
seem so urgent...
like you have to be ready
to fly today because
we don't know when they're gonna
call your number
and ask you to be a Lantern.
And the reason
we don't know is because
you were right.
The Guardians don't answer us.
You lied?
BERNADETTE:
Just because they don't answer
doesn't mean
they're not listening.
They probably don't even know
who I am.
BERNADETTE: Oh, they know
exactly who you are.
(SIGHS)
They know you better
than they knew Hal Jordan,
and they know you're better.
And the only reason
why he has that ring is
because he's been
privileged enough in this life
that he didn't have
to know fear.
And we are giving you
that same gift.
I can see it for you.
I can see you wearing
that uniform,
making us all proud. (CHUCKLES)
But I wasn't chosen.
Sometimes...
a Black man has
to raise his own hand.
Doesn't mean
you're not good enough,
doesn't mean you're not better.
It just means they don't see us.
So, we make ourselves seen.
Now, if you wanna stop trying
for this
because we lied to you,
I get it.
But you can't worry
about the choosing part.
Choose yourself.
I'm ready to shoot now.
I'll go wake up your dad.
No, not Dad.
You.
♪ (UNEASY MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
- (GUNSHOT)
- (BULLET CLATTERING)
- ♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
- (DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE)
I knew you could do it, son.
Let's go get you
your cheeseburger.
I hate cheeseburgers.
Then you don't need
to eat them anymore.
LIANNA: I admire your candor
about your family.
Why do I get the feeling
you're about to say "but"?
Because there are
still other things
you are withholding from me.
- Like my military discharge?
- LIANNA: Yes.
I've told you everything
I'm comfortable telling.
If you want this job,
you will share everything
you are uncomfortable with.
- (INSECTS CHIRPING)
- ♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
♪ (MUSIC INTENSIFIES) ♪
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC
CONTINUES) ♪
♪ (MUSIC BUILDS) ♪
(DISTANT BOOM)
(BOOMING WHOOSH)
(RUMBLING BOOM)
(ROARING WHOOSH)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
♪ (DISCORDANT MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(BOOMING WHOOSH)
(CRACKLING WHOOSH)
♪ (MUSIC FADES) ♪
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
- CHAVEZ: Nine months.
- You said it could take a while.
- CHAVEZ: That's a long while.
- That's how long it took.
We thought you were dead.
The higher-ups
were losing their shit.
You could have sent
a recon plane.
You didn't have
to send in Jordan.
We didn't.
Exactly.
(SIGHS)
The Deputy
to the Defense Secretary
was at some strip club.
And who's at the bar
holding court
but Hal fucking Jordan.
They start drinking. (SIGHS)
The Deputy lets it slide
they have intel
Gray Wolf's headed
for his retreat. Boom.
Jordan just zips up at the sky,
headed straight for Kamchatka.
Blasts the compound,
grabs Gray Wolf,
and drops him off
at Guantanamo.
So now, we have
a wanted terrorist,
not dead, but in custody.
And a bunch
of pissed-off Russians
asking who torched 300 acres
of their sovereign land.
Fortunately, the U.S. military
can take responsibility
for this shitstorm.
With one small exception.
We weren't supposed to be there.
- CHAVEZ: We were not.
- JOHN: Hmm.
And neither was Jordan.
And someone has to take the heat
lest it get out
that our foreign policy
is the solicitation of aid
from drunk fucking superheroes
in titty bars.
- SERVER: Here you go, gentlemen.
- Thank you.
Yeah, okay.
CHAVEZ: Do you know
what you're saying okay to, son?
You were there
of your own volition.
Your discharge
is gonna be dishonorable.
But everyone up top
will know the service
you've done for your country.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, I understand.
God bless you, Major.
- Hmm.
- (CHAVEZ SLURPING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
How long are you gonna mope
around my house?
As long as you'll let me.
- Fucking Hal Jordan.
- (CHUCKLES)
Fucking Hal Jordan.
Everything I worked for is gone.
Nothing you lost
can't be got back.
JOHN: That's years
of my life, Mama.
Nine months alone,
spent eating bugs and berries.
You don't eat meat anyway.
- Open it. I already did.
- What is it?
Hmm?
- I didn't apply to art school.
- BERNADETTE: I did.
- You wanna go, don't you?
- JOHN: Why would you do that?
BERNADETTE:
Because it's time for you
to pick yourself up,
and stop using up
all my electricity.
Okay, and...
what about my destiny?
The path hasn't changed.
This is just a detour.
Now, if you wanna sit up
in this room
and be scared
that it's all over,
then you're afraid.
- And if you're afraid...
- Then it's over.
BERNADETTE: Right.
Courage is fear
that's said its prayers, son.
You could be worried,
but you have to be brave enough
to still try.
Because one day,
every little boy's
gonna wanna be
just like you.
But until then,
you have to make yourself happy.
Since when did you care
if I was happy?
You still mad
about those crayons?
♪ (SOFT PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
RECRUITER:
Thank you for agreeing
to meet me, Mr. Stewart.
Thank you. Of course.
As I'm sure you were told,
we're looking
for a well-trained student
for a very special project.
You come highly recommended.
The evaluation is simple enough.
I will ask you to draw sketches
of objects from memory.
The more detailed, the better.
- Shall we?
- Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Please, sketch
the building we're in.
Can you picture a watch?
Preferably one that belonged
to your mother or father.
- Yeah, my father's.
- RECRUITER: Excellent.
Now, Mr. Stewart, please...
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
...place the ring on your finger
and manifest
your father's watch.
RECRUITER: You must consider
all of its inner engineering
if it is to work.
Just think about it.
It will project.
♪ (RIVETING INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
(RING WARBLING)
(WATCH TICKING)
Fine work.
♪ (SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC RESUMES) ♪
(DOOR LOCKING)
RECRUITER: We've been watching
your progress.
Now, off you go.
Or you'll miss your interview.
My interview?
The one you've been waiting for.
(BOOMING ECHO)
(TINKLING WARBLE)
(BURBLING RUMBLE)
Jump.
- (ECHOING WHOOSH)
- ♪ (EERIE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING) ♪
- (ECHOING THUD)
- ♪ (MUSIC CONCLUDES) ♪
Can you confirm for me
that it is because of Hal Jordan
that you are no longer
in the military?
Yeah.
Would you say that
it is because Hal Jordan
was chosen over your father
that your family life is...
complicated?
Yeah.
LIANNA: You would be closer
to your brothers?
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Yeah.
And has any of this
caused you to harbor
ill will
for Hal Jordan?
No.
You just told me
he was the reason
you were discharged
from the military.
It's not his fault.
He was following orders.
Actually, he wasn't.
In fact, we had
repeatedly admonished him
to not use his powers
to intervene
in terrestrial disputes.
Hmm.
Would you be comfortable
replacing Hal Jordan?
Understanding that he would be
under the impression
that you are simply his backup.
Are those my orders?
If you get the job, yes,
those would be your orders.
Well, then it doesn't matter
if I'm comfortable with it.
LIANNA: Congratulations...
John Stewart.
Mama! Dad!
Y'all are not gonna
believe this.
There he is.
The one and only John Stewart.
Hey, he's a junior, isn't he?
Is that what you call him?
- Uh...
- We just call him John.
Junior, Hal Jordan.
Pleasure to meet you.
- Yeah, nice to meet you.
- It is, isn't it?
I was just telling
your folks here, uh,
I just had
to meet my new protégé.
And I don't know
how in the world
the big, blue bosses chose him,
but I know that if...
well, if you two raised him,
he's gonna be top-notch.
Y'all two are salt of the Earth,
like the Midwest Huxtables.
(CHUCKLES)
Junior, what say
we walk outside
and talk over schedules
and whatnot.
And...
I do appreciate the hospitality.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- HAL JORDAN: You coming, Junior?
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
You starstruck or shy?
Uh, neither, sir.
I'm kind of getting
the sense of, uh,
tension.
No, no, it's just, um...
It just means a lot to me.
I was hoping
to tell them myself, that's all.
Aw, hell. Did I spoil it?
No. No, sir.
No, it's... It's okay.
- It is?
- JOHN: Yeah.
- It's okay?
- Yeah.
- HAL: You're sure?
- Mm-hmm.
(EXHALES SHARPLY) All right,
good, good, good, good.
Because... (HESITATES)
...you know, honestly, uh...
I don't give a flying fuck
what you're hoping for,
but I'm guessing
it's this ring right here.
And I don't need
a fucking sidekick,
and I don't want
a fucking backup,
and the only way
you're gonna get this ring
is over my dead fucking body.
We'll start training
Monday morning.
Looking forward to it, Junior.
- ♪ ("GASOLINE DREAMS"
BY OUTKAST PLAYING) ♪
- ♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ All right, all right
All right, all right ♪
All right, all right... ♪
I think he likes me.
♪ Don't everybody like
The smell of gasoline? ♪
♪ Well, burn, motherfucker
Burn American dreams ♪
♪ Don't everybody like
The taste of apple pie? ♪
♪ We'll snap
For yo' slice of life ♪
♪ I'm tellin' ya why ♪
♪ I hear that Mother Nature
Now on birth control ♪
♪ The coldest pimp be looking
For somebody to hold ♪
♪ The highway up to Heaven
Got a crook on the toll ♪
♪ Youth full of fire
Ain't got nowhere to go ♪
- ♪ Whoo! ♪
- ♪ Nowhere to go ♪
♪ Uh, all of my heroes
Did dope ♪
♪ Every nigga 'round me
Playing married ♪
♪ Or paying child support
I can't cope ♪
♪ Never made no sense to me
One day, I hope it will ♪
♪ And that's that
Sport, sport ♪
♪ Pray I live to see the day ♪
♪ When Seven's happily married
With kids ♪
♪ Wow, wow
The world is moving fast ♪
♪ And I'm losing my balance
Now it's time to dig, low, low ♪
♪ To a place where ain't nowhere
To go but up ♪
♪ You with me, say
"Shit, sho', sho'" ♪
♪ Now let me ask y'all this ♪
♪ Don't everybody like
The smell of gasoline? ♪
♪ Well, burn, motherfucker
Burn American dreams ♪
♪ Don't everybody like
The taste of apple pie? ♪
♪ We'll snap
For yo' slice of life ♪
♪ I'm tellin' ya why ♪
♪ I hear that Mother Nature
Now on birth control ♪
♪ The coldest pimp be looking
For somebody to hold ♪
♪ The highway up to Heaven
Got a crook on the toll ♪
♪ Youth full of fire
Ain't got nowhere to go ♪
- ♪ Nowhere to go ♪
- ♪ Let's hit it ♪
♪ Ricky Stratton
Got a million bucks ♪
♪ But my cousin, Ricky Walker
Got ten years doing Fed time ♪
♪ On a first offense drug bust
Fuck the ho-lice ♪
♪ That's if ya racist
Or ya crooked ♪
♪ Arrest me for this dope ♪
♪ I didn't weight it up
Or cook it ♪
♪ You gotta charge the world ♪
♪ 'Cause over a million people
Took it ♪
♪ Look at me
I'm outta your jurisdiction ♪
♪ Now ya lookin' stupid
Officer, get off me, sir ♪
♪ Don't make me call L.A.
He'll have ya walking, sir ♪
♪ A couple of months ago
They gave OutKast ♪
♪ The key to the city ♪
♪ But I still gotta pay my taxes
And they give us no pity ♪
♪ About these youngsters
Amongst us ♪
♪ You think
They respect the law ♪
♪ They think they monsters
They love us ♪
♪ Reality rappin' ♪
♪ And giving the youth
The truth from this booth ♪
♪ And when we on stage
We scream ♪
♪ "Don't everybody, everybody" ♪
♪ Don't everybody like
The smell of gasoline? ♪
♪ Well, burn, motherfucker
Burn American dreams ♪
♪ Don't everybody like
The taste of apple pie? ♪
♪ We'll snap
For yo' slice of life ♪
♪ I'm tellin' ya why ♪
♪ I hear that Mother Nature
Now on birth control ♪
- ♪ The coldest pimp be looking
For somebody to hold... ♪
- ♪ (SONG CONCLUDES) ♪